Wolff, Sidney A. Additional Arbitration Files 5637
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Sidney A. Wolff Additional Arbitration Files
1954-1978
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wolff, Sidney
5637
12 cubic feet
12 linear ft.
Records (documents), collective labor agreements.
Arbitration files involving United Steelworkers of America (USWA); Teamsters (IBT); Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union (OCAW); International Association of Machinists (IAM); Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU); International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW); Communication Workers of America (CWA); United Auto Workers (UAW); International Union of Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers (IUE); and others.
5685186
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 02, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 06, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5131: Sidney A. Wolff Arbitration Files
Arbitration, Industrial; Collective bargaining; Wolff, Sidney.; Allied Chemical Corporation; American Cyanamid Company; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company; Display Die Cutter Company; Dresser Industries, Inc.; United Steelworkers; Ford Instrument Company; Givaudan Corporation; Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union. Local 8-559; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Jamaica Water Supply Company; Utility Workers Union of America; Kollsman Instrument Corporation; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union; National Broadcasting Company; New England Telephone and Telegraph Company; New Jersey Bell Telephone Company; Communications Workers of America; Otis Elevator Company; International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers; Western Electric Company; Westinghouse Electric Corporation; New York Telephone Company; British Overseas Airways Corporation; Eastern Air Lines; Northwest Airlines, Inc.; Air Line Pilots Association; International Association of Machinists; Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America
5685186
- A - Carborundum (Box 1)
  - Accurate Brass Corporation and United Steelworkers of America, Local 6738 (United States of America) -, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    includes general correspondence, supporting documentation, transcripts (1 volume), award, arbitrator's report and fee statement, manuscript notes
  - Addamo, Pete and the Journeymen Barbers, cosmetologists, and Proprietors International Union of America Local 15 - Contract validity and liability of employers for Pension and Welfare Plan payment, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    includes: general correspondence, award, report of panel arbitrator, manuscript notes
  - Adele Construction Company and the Stationary Engineers Local 670 -, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    general correspondence
  - Aeronautical Radio, Incorporated and International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 202, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    general correspondence only
  - Allied Chemical Corporation, Fibers Division and United Mine Workers of America District 50, Local 13942 - discharge, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    general correspondence, manuscript notes, award, transcripts (1 volume), pamphlet - "Hourly Employees Group Insurance Benefit," company brief, Union Post-Hearing Brief, supporting documentation
  - Allied Chemical Corporation (Fibers Division) and the United Mine Workers of America (District 50), Local 13942, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    includes general correspondence, manuscript notes, supporting documentation, union post hearing brief, opening statement submitted on behalf of the Union, award, transcripts, memorandum (1963)
  - Allied Chemical Corporation, National Aniline Division, Company brief - issue: plant shutdown and the failure to apply seniority on a sectional basis as required by the Contract and past practice in the shutdown, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Allied Chemical Corporation and the International Union of District 50, United Mine Workers of America Local 13942 - issue: holiday work schedule, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes proceedings, general correspondence, company brief, manuscript notes, Union's opening statement, opinion and award, Union post hearing brief, supporting documentation, company brief, opening statement (Grievance arbitration)
  - Allied Chemical Corporation and United Steelworkers of America, Local 12457 - issue: discharge (Box 1, Folder 9)
    includes award, manuscript notes, supporting documentation, manuscript notes, general correspondence
  - Alpha Tank and International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers, Local 455 - issue: failure of employer to pay wage increases to its employees, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    includes general correspondence
  - Amalgamated Local Union 355, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    correspondence only
  - American Cyanamid Company and International Chemical Workers - overtime distribution (Box 1, Folder 12)
    general correspondence, arbitrator statement and fees, manuscript notes, award, supporting documentation, union brief, general correspondence
  - American Cyanamid and International Chemical Workers Union Local III, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Cyanamid Company and the United Steelworkers of America, District 9, Local 12426 - discharge, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    general correspondence, arbitrator's report and fee statement, award, manuscript notes, supporting documentation, opinion and award
  - American Cyanamid Company and the International Chemical Workers Union, Local III - work assignment and job classification, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    arbitrator's statement and fees, general correspondence, award, supporting documentation
  - Amerace-ESNH versus UAW, Local 726, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Home Products and OCAWIU (Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union), Local 8-828-, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Home Products Corporation and OCAWIU Local 8-124, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - American Nurses Association and the Community and Social Agency Employees Union Local 1707 - job classification, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    general correspondence, memo opinion, manuscript notes, American Nurses' Association (position description), supporting documentation
  - American Paper Company, Incorporated, and the United Paperworkers International Union Local 706 - wage rates, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    general correspondence, manuscript notes, award, supporting documentation
  - American Robin FLM Joint Board United Mechanics 150 - violation of seniority, job security, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    general correspondence, manuscript notes, award
  - American Smelting and Refining Company Federated Metals Division, and the UAW Local 143 - Discipline, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Smelting and Refining Company, Baltimore Plant, and the United Steelworkers of America Local 625 - refusing to give grievant a job, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    general correspondence, award, and opinion; arbitrator's report and fee statement, manuscript notes, Union Brief, Company Brief, opinion and award, general correspondence
  - Anaconda American Brass Company and the United Steelworkers of America, District 1 - suspension, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    general correspondence, supporting documentation, manuscript notes, unions memo, company post hearing brief
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith and the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, Staff Personnel Committee - discharge, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Applebush, Incorporated and Motion Picture Film Editors Local 771 - discharge, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    general correspondence, supporting documentation, award
  - Armstrong Cork Company and the Federal Labor Union Local 22703 - contract interpretation and seniority in promotion, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    general correspondence, supporting documentation, manuscript notes, opinion and award (FMCS decision and also arbitration proceedings)
  - Armstrong Cork Company and the United Rubber Workers Union Local 285 - suspension, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    manuscript notes, general correspondence, supporting documentation, award
  - A.W. Fabrics, Incorporated and the Amalgamated Meat Cutter and Butcher Workmen of North America Local 251, AFL-CIO - discharge, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    general correspondence, award, manuscript notes, award
  - Basf Wyandotte Corporation and International Chemical Workers Union Local 846- disciplinary action, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    award, general correspondence, supporting documentation
  - Bayside Chrysler Plymouth, Incorporated and the Teamsters Local 868 - vacations, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Beech - Nut Life Savers, Incorporated and the Beech Nut Employees' Association - discharge, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    general correspondence, supporting documentation, manuscript notes, award, union reply brief, company's response to union brief, company brief, union submission of brief, stipulation
  - Becker, Esther and Accent of Theater Parties - lump sum payments, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    consent award, general correspondence, manuscript notes
  - Birchwood Nursing Home and National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, Local 1199 - contributions to the Hospital League regarding Training and Upgrading Fund, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Borden, Incorporated versus IAM Local 1180 - classification, rate of pay, seniority, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    manuscript notes, award, agreement (1967), general correspondence, supporting documentation
  - Borden Metal Products Company and Teamsters Local 102 - vacation pay, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    award, general correspondence, supporting documentation, manuscript notes
  - Breyer's Ice Cream - Division of Kraftco Corporation and the IAM District 15 - suspension and discharge, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    award, manuscript notes, supporting documentation, and general correspondence
  - Bronx Brass Foundry and the United Steel Workers of America Local 13908 - call in pay, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    report of panel arbitrator, manuscript notes, award
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 2230 - promotion and upgrading, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    award, manuscript notes, general correspondence, supporting documentation, Agreement (1968), laboratory reply to the Union's memorandum in support of Union Position, closing statement of the Laboratory, memorandum in support of Union position
  - Brownstone Productions, Incorporated and American Federation of Television and Radio Artists - lump payment, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    general correspondence, manuscript notes, award, notice of intention to Arbitrate and demand for arbitration
  - C and P Telephone Company and the Communication Workers of America- temporary promotions, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    general correspondence, transcripts, manuscript notes, award
  - Canada Dry Corporation and the teamsters Local 282 - Job duties of transfer drives and compensation rates, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    award, arbitration bill, manuscript notes
  - The Carborundum Company and the Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union Local 8-490 - violation of the Bereavement Clause, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    opinion and award, arbitration bill, general correspondence, supporting documentation, manuscript notes
- Cardinal - Calls (Box 2)
  - Cardinal McCloskey Home and Mary Helen Evans - discharge, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Celanese Fibers Company and the Textile Workers Union of America Local 2024, 1093, 1874, 1384; UMW District 50 Local 15153; Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union Local 2024 (8 issues), 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Issues: Work assignments (1974); suspension (1976); wage rates upon transfer (1975); welders protest assignment of work (1974); work load; subcontracting (1975-1976); absency policy (1974); transfers and filling job vacancies (1974) Materials include: transcripts, general correspondences, supporting documentation, opinions and awards, company briefs, union briefs, pamphlet "Your Guide" (contains information on policy, practices and procedures of the plant), telegrams, Decisions and Recommendations (Labor Relations Reporter), manuscript notes, Agreement (1973), Demands for Arbitration
  - Celanese Plastics Company and TWUA - promotion/job classification (1968). Equalization of overtime (1970), 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    includes general correspondence, manuscript notes, company briefs, union brief, transcripts, supporting documentation
  - Chair Super 6 Incorporated versus Allied ? Union - issue: wages, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    decision, correspondence Handwriting illegible; return to folder for information
  - Chamberlin Corporation and United Steelworkers of America (no local) - suspension, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    award, manuscript notes, general correspondence, supporting documentation
  - Chase Bag Company and the United Paperworkers International Union Local 11666 - seniority, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    general correspondence supporting documentation, manuscript notes, transcripts, Decisions and recommendations from the Labor Relation Reporter, Agreement (1975), Company post-hearing brief, union brief
  - Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company versus Communication Workers of America District 2 -, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    only correspondence
  - Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company versus Communication Workers of America District 2 -, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chevron Oil Company and the Teamsters Local 1866 - discharge, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    general correspondence, supporting documentation, award and opinion, manuscript notes, company brief
  - Ciba-Geigy Corporation and Chemical Workers Union (no local) -, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cities Service Company, Incorporated, and the United Steelworkers of America Local 1670 - seniority rights, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    union brief, general correspondence, supporting documentation, manuscript notes, company post hearing brief, union brief
  - Clark Equipment Company, Industrial Truck Division and US IAM local 447 - layoff, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    award and opinion, manuscript notes, supporting documentation, general correspondence
  - Cleveland Electric Illuminating Company and the Utility Workers Union of America Local 270 - overtime pay, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    opinion and award, company brief, union post hearing brief, transcript, general correspondence, supporting documentation
  - Cleveland Electric Illuminating Company and Utility Workers Union of America Local 270 - Issue: Discharge for physical disability, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    transcripts, manuscript notes, company brief, union post hearing brief, arbitration opinion and award, general correspondence
- Colts - Frame (Box 3)
  - Colt's Incorporated and UAW - seniority and overtime rights, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    award and opinion, arbitrators' bill, union brief, company brief, manuscript notes, transcripts (3 volumes), general correspondence
  - Computerized Steel Fabrication and Shopmen's Local Union Local 455 - recall, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    general correspondence, manuscript notes
  - Continental Can Company, Incorporated, and the United Steelworkers of America Local 6607 - discharge, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cooper Bessemer Corporation and USWA - Seniority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    general correspondence, award and opinion, manuscript notes, supporting documentation, transcript
  - Coty Incorporated and Teamsters - suspension, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    general correspondence, award and opinion, manuscript notes
  - Curtiss-Wright Corporation and the IAM Local 703 - dental plan, restoration of cafeteria operations, lump sum payment, allowance and accrued payment, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    general correspondence, arbitration bill, opinion and award, manuscript notes, supplemental agreement (1971), supporting documentation, Agreement (1969)
  - D'Armigne Incorporated versus Local 107 ILGWU -, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Development Corporation for Israel and Community and Social Agency Employees Union, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees Local 1707 - overload of work, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    arbitration bill, general correspondence, opinion and award, Agreement (1969), manuscript notes, company memorandum, union memorandum, supporting documentation
  - Display Die Cutter Company vs. United Paperworkers Local 107 -, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Display Die Cutter Company vs. United Paperworkers Local 107 -, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Correspondence only
  - Dixie Container Company and the United Paperworkers International Union Local 697 - Work Shortage, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Decisions and Recommendations from the Labor Relations Reporter, general correspondence, award and opinion, manuscript notes, company brief, post hearing union brief
  - Doctors Hospital and the Hotel and Allied Service Employees Union Local 144 - employment status ("regular" or temporary employees), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    general correspondence, opinion and award, manuscript notes, supporting documentation
  - Dow Chemical versus United Paperworkers Local 793 -, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Drake Bakeries and Bakery and Confectionate Workers International Union Local 3 - Call in pay and week's notice of layoff, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    general correspondence, manuscript notes, supporting documentation
  - Dresser Industries and United Steelworkers - contract interpretation or application, transfer, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    arbitrator's report and fee statement, general correspondence, manuscript notes, supporting documentation "contract" and "arbitrator's" are both partially cut off; assumed to be correct interpretation
  - Dresser Industries and United Steelworkers of America, Incorporated, Local 1630 Transportation Equipment Division - overtime: did not pay employees extra for time sent in compensation hearing (Box 3, Folder 16)
    opinion and award, arbitration report and fee statement, general correspondence, company post-opinion brief, company opening statement, supporting documentation, union brief
  - Dunham Bush Incorporated and Capitol City Lodge, IAM Local 3514 - suspension of shop committee, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - (DuPont) Trust of Eugene DuPont and Trust of Nicholas DuPont as assignees of Ridco Properties, Incorporated and Stephen C. Lyras versus Chemical Workers Local 527 - payment of lump sum monies, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Petitioner's prehearing memorandum, general correspondence, transcripts, respondent's prehearing memorandum, manuscript notes
  - Eagle Pet Service Company, Incorporated and Bakery Drivers Union Local 550 - discharge, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Educator Biscuit Company and Beech Nut Incorporated, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Emery Air Freight vs. Local 295 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    folder empty
  - Erie, County of and the Faculty Federation of Erie Community College -failure to provide adequate working conditions (secretary/faculty ratio), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    general correspondence, demand for arbitration
  - Esterline Precision Automation Corporation and IAM District 15 - merit increase, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    general correspondence, manuscript notes, award and opinion, supporting documentation
  - Fairchild-Hiller Corporation and IAM Local 893 -, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Arbitration bill, award, manuscript notes, supporting documentation
  - Fairchild Republic vs. IAM Local 1987 - job classification, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Fast Service Shipping Terminals, Incorporated, and Pierre Babb, Aurelio M. Casanovas, Peter Kastanis, Eugene Mercer, Leehunt A. Nurse, Eric Skeet and William J. Simon - lump sum payment, 1954-1967 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    general correspondence, manuscript notes, award, Agreement (1954), memorandum (1967), trial memorandum on behalf of the claimants, Agreement (1962), Agreement (1960); also includes: "A Manual for Commercial Arbitrators" put out by the AAA and a pamphlet "Commercial Arbitration Rules of the AAA" (1964)
  - Fitchburg Paper Company and the Teamsters Local 16 - down bidding within a department, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Ford Instrument Company and IUE Local 471 - monies due, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Ford Instrument Company and International Union of Electrical Radio Local 471 and Machine Workers - travel classifications and monies due, 1956- 1964 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Agreement (1956 and 1964), general correspondence, manuscript notes, supporting documentation
  - Ford Instrument Company and Engineering, Technical, and Clerical Federation - International Union Of Electrical Radio and Machine Workers Local 471 - job classification and wage rate, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    general correspondence, supporting documentation, transcripts, manuscript notes, award
  - Frame Chevrolet and Amalgamated Union Local 335 -, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Frito-Lay versus Teamsters Local 802 -, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Frito-Lay - Jova (Box 4)
  - GAF Corporation and the IAM Local 506 - work being performed by the wrong bargaining unit, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    award and opinion, manuscript notes, correspondence (general, supporting documentation)
  - GAF and International Chemical Workers Local 227 -, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General Electric - Local Lodge 1669, District 1, 5, 7, and IAM -, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General Cable Corporation and the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 868 - Discharge, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Arbitration report and fee statement, general correspondence, manuscript notes
  - General Cable Corporation and the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 868 - job protection/transfer, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    correspondence (general), manuscript notes, company post hearing brief, award and opinion, supporting documentation
  - General Floorcraft, Incorporated and International Union of Electrical Workers (IUE) Local 385 - discharge, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    general correspondence, manuscript notes, Agreement (1976)
  - Givaudan Corporation and O.C.A.W. Local 8-559 - suspension (Box 4, Folder 7)
    opinion and award, manuscript notes, arbitration statement and fee, supporting documentation, general correspondence
  - Givaudan Corporation and OCAW Local 8-559 - contract interpretation, discharge (Box 4, Folder 8)
    manuscript notes, general correspondence, supporting documentation
  - Givaudan Corporation versus OCAW Local 8-559 -, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Givaudan Corporation versus OCAW Local 8-559 -, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Givaudan Corporation versus OCAW Local 8-559 -, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Givaudan Corporation versus OCAW Local 8-559 -, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    discharge
  - Givaudan Corporation versus OCAW Local 8-559 - Bumping, Retirement, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Grossman Steel and Aluminum Corporation and the Shopmen's Local Union $455 - Representation on Local #455 - Trust Fund and the improper payment of Employees vacation and sick-leave funds, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    general correspondence, Agreement and Declaration of Trust - Local #455 Industry Vacation Trust Fund (1970), Memorandum on Behalf of Local #455, Reply Memorandum of Law of Grossman Steel and Aluminum Corporation, Claimant, Memorandum of Law of Grossman Steel and Aluminum Corporation, Claimant, manuscript notes, award and opinion